[Music]
IL Cafe we have you
covered a podcast on how technology
drives innovation in the insurance
industry good to have you join us on
episode 2 of I Cafe I'm your host sheal
and the topic of conversation today is
ESG and its impact on the insurance
industry Our Guest on the podcast is
gopal balachandran Chief Financial
Officer and chief risk officer at IC
lombar he's also a pioneer of excellence
in financial reporting and corporate
governance for India INC now let me tell
you a little bit more about gopal he's
been associated with icso lombar for
nearly two decades and wears several
hats uh he heads finance and accounts
investor relations risk management mid
and back office Investments as well as
internal control and loss minimization
functions he was also instrumental in
icso Lombard becoming the first Indian
non-life insurance company to be listed
and he's received wide Acclaim and
recognition for his work including
Awards like the financial Express best
CFO of the year and the CFO 100 award in
different categories like Risk
Management cost management and financial
reporting so on this episode of I Cafe
gives me great joy to have gopal tell us
about that which is top of mind for
insurance organizations across the world
today today ESG thanks so much gopal for
joining us on I Cafe welcome to the show
and how are you very good Shel thank you
thank you thanks for that uh kind
introduction I don't kind of deserve so
much of it but thank you so much for
that well gopal I'm certainly every bit
of that is deserved and thank you for
joining us one more time now uh to get
started right ESG efforts have certainly
become a significant differentiator for
responsible Enterprises and icso Lombard
clearly a Mari brand in India the second
largest General Insurance company in
India for fy20 22 and also Pioneer of
sorts has also demonstrated leadership
in the adoption of ESG as part of its
growth strategy so I'd love to hear from
you on that gopal the company's
sustainability goals some of the focus
areas and some of the efforts that have
been undertaken in this regard that's a
that's a great start Shel so I think
when you look at it you started off by
saying that we are the first non-life uh
insurance company to be listed on the
stock exchanges in India right given the
fact that we are a responsible
institution and therefore clearly ESG is
something that uh we kind of largely im
as an organization as a part of uh
running the institutions not just for
one or two years but over several
decades right is how we are looking at
ESG as a space to kind of embrace as a
part of the way we work your point on
how do we kind of look at the space u I
think honestly I will kind of divide it
into a couple of aspects uh one is if if
you look at in terms of what we have
been doing as a company I think we
started off disclosures well ahead of
mandatory timelines of uh reporting in
this particular space just to kind of
give an example the ESG report that we
put out publicly on our website this has
been the third year in the running so
that's something that we' have been
doing on an ongoing basis right uh as
you would recollect I think there was
this new mandate which actually is
coming into force from fi
2023 which is the business
responsibility and sustainability report
in requirements for the top th000 listed
companies now while this is mandatory
for fi23 we thought even an institution
that's largely responsible and
sustainable let kind of voluntary
adopted it from one year before so as a
part of our fi 2022 annual report we
also had a separate section on the brsr
as it is kind of largely known as as an
Acron we wanted to kind of start ahead
of time so that's something that we have
been pioneering in kind of taking
initiatives well ahead of deadlines that
are stipulated for companies to kind of
comply with if I were to kind of just
move move forward while I said that we
have been doing the disclosures on
volary basis but honestly I think the
large part of it is primarily because we
have been kind of able to engage
significantly with multiple stakeholders
and when we say stakeholders it spans
across customers Regulators our
shareholders reinsurers our own
employees government I think all of them
have been a part of our journey in kind
of getting appropriate feedback
mechanism so that we can kind of improve
our disclosures better so there has been
extensive engagement with stakeholders
that we have been doing as a company now
while we've been doing that I think
obviously the tone is always set from
the top the board is very very actively
involved we always had a corporate
social responsibility committee but in
order to kind of embrace it with the
flavor of sustainability we also kind of
we renamed it as CSR and sustainability
committee so that's kind of gives a
flavor to from the top the boards are
actively involved in the design and the
framework of the ESG that we want to
kind of run as an institution so clearly
there is board oversight that's the
third thing that we' have been kind of
focusing on right and the fourth piece
that I would say is I think I say again
as a company which is responsible on um
effective disclosures uh as I said this
year in fact was the first year where we
also started disclosing sustainability
disclosures across the various scope one
2 and three emissions that we do as a
company we kind of again did that
sustainability disclosures for the first
time as a part of the F22 report more
importantly we also were able to get an
assurance done by an independent
external firm to validate the
disclosures that we put out as a part of
the report that in a sense are those
four or five key pillars in the way we
look at ESG as an organization important
takeaway for all of our listeners I
would imagine is that having a Buy in
from the leadership levels is something
that can certainly drive your ESG agenda
a lot better the other thing that comes
to mind gopal is that there has been a
growing emphasis in the larger Financial
sphere globally on sustainability for
example we've seen a lot of uh talk
around sustainability linked loans and
other such you know nuanced approaches
uh similarly the insurance industry has
pursued sustainability goals in its own
way so what significant to tangible
changes do you think we likely to see in
the insurance sector over the next uh
decade or so okay that's a great
question because we are looking at maybe
the future right right so I'm sure maybe
amongst the audience who is kind of
possibly listening to me a lot of a lot
of them would have possibly in their
minds are already thinking about the
next vehicle that um he or she is likely
to buy should be an electric one right
now it doesn't matter whe two wheer or
four-wheeler but effectively I think
there is a clear need for transitioning
into move to move to electric vehicles
but that's a reality and clearly we know
that electric vehicles are relatively
far better in so far as uh promoting the
sustainability theme is concerned and in
that regard I think from an Isis Lombard
standpoint we have been Pioneers in
providing Insurance Solutions for this
transition to electric vehicles
Mobility uh just to kind of put some
data points on the table on the electric
vehicle space I mean for the just the
quarter that had kind of Gone by on the
private car side we roughly had a market
share of about almost 14% And on the two
wheeler space which which we think will
kind of largely transition faster into
adoption of eveve there we have a
substantial market share of almost 65%
uh the number is quite high at this
point of time though over a period of
time we believe it could get moderated
so but that's one area where we want to
kind of see ourselves taking the lead in
possibly offering Insurance Solutions on
the electric vehicles segment so that's
one yeah the other area sh I'm sure all
of us will be kind of uh uh looking
forward to kind of see our
entire power consumptions getting moved
into solar power or renewable forms of
uh energy consumptions there again I
think we have been Pioneers in that
space of being able to offer Insurance
Solutions to some of these capabilities
and that's again a segment that has done
very well for us so as a company as a
responsible institution we would want to
see how we can partner some of these
corporates or institutions to be able to
transition into some of the
sustainability themes that they would be
kind of working towards right so that's
one area which I would say in terms of
how one can look forward the second um
what we have seen in the last couple of
years particularly during the covid uh
environment all of us clearly learned
how to work digital that obviously means
uh across the spectrum of your
operations you could see increased
adoption of digital SL technology and
that by itself is going to kind of lend
a significant amount in so far as
promoting sustainability is concerned
because we are all going to see maybe
reduced consumption of maybe paper
travel reduction of footprint and so on
and so forth so clearly that's going to
be an area which uh we like to see for
the future and the third area again I
would say from an um insurance company
standpoint uh an area which we will be
significantly focusing on is responsible
Investments there again today from an is
lomard stand point we already have a
responsible investing framework which is
largely based on the principles of un
principles of responsible investing um
where we look at maybe getting insights
from investe companies in the way how
they are promoting sustainability uh we
do have an exclusion list in terms of U
assets where we want to kind of make our
investments in so clearly I think uh
both on uh offering Insurance Solutions
which kind of uh takes care of
responsible underwriting and at the same
time responsible Investments is equally
a theme that we're working on now you
spoke of Technology but it would be
remiss of me to not dwell a little bit
more gopal because we know that
technology oh what can we do without it
now right but I'm quite certain that
icic Lombard has taken it to another
level uh from the point of view how
you've leveraged these Innovations and
also digitalization what what have you
done in the organization so from our
standpoint I think that when we talk of
digital uh it kind of cuts acoss across
the entire spectrum of uh the way we
Source policies the way we service our
uh claim proposition and more
importantly the way we kind of digitize
our internal processes uh that's the way
we look at uh digital SL use of
Technology uh Innovation across the
various areas that we operate on right
last couple of years we had seen tough
times on covid environment but over the
last so many years of our operations I
think we have been a firm believer in
technology right let me give you
examples of how we are leveraging uh
technology in the way we operate let me
take uh a relatively simpler one motor
insurance MH now all of us know as in
when a claim happens we are all in a
hurry to get our claim serviced that's
what we want we want our vehicles back
at the shortest possible time now there
again we take a lot of initiatives in
making sure that we can speeden the
process of survey of the vehicle and in
the process the customer is able to
possibly get the vehicle back on time
over the last s years I would say that
we developed um app inasp app now what
this app essentially does is when a
vehicle goes for survey at the garage
the garage is able to use the app and
through a live video streaming process
our experienced claim service managers
who is sitting at a remote location is
able to look at the video which is
streaming live and there is a voice over
that is happening between the claim
service manager and the L person MH and
in the process you able to significantly
kind of be more efficient in the entire
survey process this has been a great
enabler for us in processing the claims
much faster and today more than 85% of
our claims that we settle on the motor
own damage side uses this inasp app and
in the process we have been able to
create customer Delight in the way we
settle claims on uh motor insurance
that's one example on of motor even on
the policy buying process many of times
customers May tend to possibly miss the
renewal date so in the process
effectively you may be without an
insurance at the point of expiry of your
last policy but given the fact that you
want to have a continuing insurance
cover there is a process which is called
as break-in inspection because you would
want to see whether the vehicle was
already having a damage at the time of
the renewal process in case if you have
missed the renewal date there again I
think with the help of Technology we
created a app by which the entire
break-in process is quite seamless the
customer can actually undertake a self
inspection of the break-in process and
in the process if everything is clean
it's a kind of a green channel for the
renewal process to happen so there again
I think a very large proportion of our
Breakin process is significantly done
through use of digital SL technology and
in the process getting
customer experience which is POS
positive um we move to health quickly uh
if you look at health I think one of the
things again we have been a firm
believer of using technology in the
health insurance phace as well the IL
take care app which is again something
that we created to largely Advocate uh
the health insurance proposition though
increasingly we are expanding the
products that we can offer through the
app but that's again a capability which
significantly helps in the health
insurance segment uh one other example
if you to talk about on the use of
technology in the health side is a
typical pain point for a customer uh at
the time of seeking a cashless
authorization at the hospitals is always
something that we generally get to hear
about uh most of us would have faced
that for unfortunate reasons in case if
any of us have to get admitt at the
hospitals there again use of Technology
we significantly streamlined the entire
cashless authorization process which
used to run into maybe few hours which
obviously is a painful process for the
customer today with the help of
AI ml mechanisms what used to take as I
said more than 3 4 hours the cash L
authorization for a select set of
procedures is down to less than 90
seconds uh again I think a clear
Innovation that we were able to do on
the technology side the last time uh you
know Girish nyak was here and he was
telling about the cool ways in which
technology is leveraged to offer value
or deliver impact to all stakeholders
and primarily of course customers in his
particular case and he spoke about
calcan and I was like wo you know that
Samosa that I'm about to eat you're
going to tell me exactly how many
calories it has and now you're telling
me about things like inpec it's all
fascinating how you know technology is
helping us achieve this very very
important um you know objective for IC
Lumbard but a lot of our listeners I'm
quite certain you too gopal must have
been wondering why is sheel asking me so
much about technology and where is the
connection to ESG so I'm coming to that
now gopal we need to dwell a little bit
more because here is a country where you
are certainly seeing people getting more
and more comfortable in using Tech in
financial transactions and also in their
investment options uh is this an
accurate assessment according to you or
would you say that this adoption that we
talk about by consumers is still too
nent to actually contribute to the
industry sustainability efforts in a
sense I'm asking you to connect the dots
between your ESG uh efforts and
Technology adoption when Co happened I
think we all had to sudden change the
way we had to operate uh we have been so
used to operating in a physical world we
had to significantly transform ourselves
into digital world and believe me some
of these capabilities were already
available with us is just that we did
not want to kind of possibly explore and
make the best use of it today the way
most of the organizations would like to
operate on is in hybrid environment it
should be a combination of both physical
plus digital customers again have kind
of learned because they are used to to
availing different forms of services
insurance is definitely one of them and
they have also kind of migrated
themselves from doing it completely in a
physical world into I would say more a
hybrid environment of operating so yes
your point is absolutely right I think
the customer preferences are clearly
moving towards use of Technology use of
digital as a way to
operate in our process of sustainability
where we are saying a large part of our
offering will be made available through
the digital means we see a significant
positive adoption from a customer
standpoint as well that's where when I
look at it on the policy side for
example we issue roughly close to 29
million policies on an annual basis of
that 97 98% of those policies do not
even enter our office so there is either
capability created at the hands of the
customer who is able to do the
requirements on their own or my inter or
distributor is able to get it done
through the customer again and digital
form so clearly I think customer are
embracing digital SL technology far far
better and in the process as you rightly
mentioned it has been a key enabler or
contributor to the sustainable
initiatives that any which ways we are
focusing as an organization you know
gopal I was just thinking about it a few
years ago you know when there was talk
of uh driving digital transformation
across sectors and organizations um a
lot of leaders spoke of how this is a
function of culture you need to have the
right organizational culture to drive DT
and I think the same is probably true of
ESG as well one of the major hurdles
that organizations will have to overcome
is a lack of knowledge and skills in
their best practices so how does icso
Lombard plan to train and equip its
Workforce to understand these important
issues like sustainable Finance uh
social and environmental risk management
and also the pivot towards
sustainability as a differential element
in customer value how are we approaching
this now as an organization on the
social responsibilities side that's an
area where our employees actually
volunteer for some of these initiatives
one is you obviously as an institution
need to build a culture to embrace
either social responsibility or ESG as a
part of uh the way we operate a lot of
our employees have been kind of
volunteering for some of this social
initiatives that we have been running
and they say that we will take the lead
in shaping up some of the agenda for the
organization so clearly there is already
a cultural mindset in the employees to
make sure that they Embrace social
responsibility on the ESG front again we
have taken employees taking the lead on
the E part of the framework I think a
lot of our employees have clearly
demonstrated areas where we as an
organization can kind of look forward
for some of those elements to be kind of
implemented they've done it at their
homes they've done it through some of
the social work that some of them may be
carrying out and clearly they are giving
us ideas to Isis Lombard by which we can
Embrace some of these elements as a way
we want to kind of promote
sustainability that's clearly
volunteering is one thing that's kind of
already working as a culture for the
institution the second is uh capability
building sessions that we undertake
across spectrum of the organization and
more importantly I think we always keep
uh kind of pushing our people to say
that why don't we look at something each
one of us can take the lead in so far as
sustainability is concerned so that's
how we kind of largely promote uh
through volunteering initiatives and to
a lot of capability building SL cultural
sessions is what we kind of embrace as
an organization so perfect coming
together of uh employee aspirations and
organizational objectives want us to
dwell a little bit more on that s aspect
of our ESG goals diversity equity and
inclusion uh gopal and the start of the
year I recall a lot of Consulting
organizations talking about how de will
remain in sharp Focus for organizations
and the Dei ethos in most organizations
is something that contributes to
Innovation productivity and also
profitability so the business imperative
has been long established would be great
for us to know what IC Lombard's policy
is regarding these important aspects of
ESG uh inclusivity equity and diversity
no so again that's a great question shal
and um that's something that's again the
need of the hour uh and as a largely
spoken topic and from an ICC Lombard
standpoint we equally committed on the
Dei uh initiative in that regard uh
there is already a cross functional
committee that we have created in the
organization which is primarily
responsible for Designing planning
driving and monitoring the
implementation of the Dei interventions
the tone is set from the top internally
on the gender equity we already have
taken U goals to achieve over the next
let's say 3 years across the various
verticals across the various divisions
in the organization each one of them is
championing this agenda of bringing
about gender equity in the organization
so that's one uh form of diversity
equity and and inclusion the second
element is uh to also make sure that uh
when you look at the entire uh working
environment uh we need to embrace people
of different work strings or people who
have got different uh requirements to be
able to contribute to the organizational
sustainability initiatives you need to
create more a flexible way of operating
for people so that you get people from
different uh requirements a part of the
organizational initiatives and there
again I think from an is Lumar
standpoint we launched flexib working
part-time working uh which are all great
enablers for us to be able to get the
right set of talent can contribute as I
said in so far as the organizational
growth is concerned even in so far as uh
employee uh initiatives are concerned we
do carry out a lot of uh annual checkups
counseling programs yoga sessions uh so
all in all the whole objective is to
make sure that uh uh Dei is pretty much
a part and parcel of the organization
right I'm glad you also touched upon
employee well-being as an important you
know pillar of all that you are building
for uh the ESG strategy at IC Lombard
you know uh gopal now I want to go back
to something that you had mentioned
sometimes I this idea just like chunkos
in my head and then I have to ask this
has got to do with the you know
volunteer work and CSR that you spoke of
uh would be wonderful for our listeners
to get a a sense of some of these
Flagship programs that you might have uh
done which made a big difference in
several locations and communities uh
tell us a little bit about the IC
Lombard's sustainability agenda and CSR
activities and how those two come
together I think for I Lombard social
responsibility is something that we are
quite cognizant of uh and some of our
initiatives in this space dates back
almost close to 10 years and the reason
why I'm saying this is we Embrace social
responsibility not just to meet the
minimum regulatory stipulations that
came in some time back but for us uh
social responsibility is a way of
operating right to safety right problem
for us in India today is we
unfortunately a lot of people succumb to
Accidental deaths and the primary reason
for some of this is uh for whatever
reason helmets are not being worn so
that's an area where we wanted to kind
of step in and uh there have been
specifically designed helmets that has
been crafted for use uh again these
helmets are being offered not only to
the parent or the person who is kind of
driving the vehicle sometimes you will
also have the child sitting at the back
uh so we realized that or maybe there
was also a demand from some of the
parents to say that why don't you also
offer a helmet for the child as well so
these are specifically designed and
crafted helmets that has been created in
order to make sure that um the country
becomes a much better place to ride
vehicles and the extent of damage or the
extent of unfortunate deaths uh could
kind of be significantly minimized so
that's one of the flagship programs that
we have been running as an organization
since the time we have been doing this
almost close to 4 lakh 25,000 lives is
what we have impacted as a result of the
right to safety initiative if you were
to move away from let's say vehicle to
um carrying hands a lot of um employees
of the organization almost more than 50%
of them actually volunteer to uh work on
this initiative the whole objective is
to kind of make sure that children are
given uh a better place to read we do a
lot of U free eye checkups so that the
problem statements gets detected ahead
of time and in case for some reason if
any of the children needs spectacles we
also make those uh spectacles available
as well uh we have impacted more than 3
lak 75,000 lives as a part of this uh
pioneering effort that we've been doing
over the last several years the third
area which also contribute significantly
to sustainability as well is safe
drinking water we call it nangali
um again we work with schools the whole
objective is to make sure that children
get Safe Drinking Water um and we kind
of install water purifiers at the
schools uh including taking care of the
maintenance of those purifiers uh uh so
that's again an initiative which is very
close to us from a social responsibility
standpoint absolutely as they say miles
to go but then Kudos most certainly
gopal to you and the teams involved in
all of these projects for actually
making such a difference and such
diverse get you know relevant areas to
ICC Lombard in the area of CSR superb to
hear of this and on a final note gopal
one of ICC Lombard's motos if I may add
is fulfill promises responsibly and
sustainably how do you see icso Lombard
playing a leadership role in the
insurance sectors push towards achieving
their ESG goals that's that's a
difficult one right because it's always
T to kind of figure out how we stay
ahead of the curve in shaping of the
elements of future we have generally
taken the lead in some of these areas
for us the first and the foremost thing
that we will obviously stand committed
is the country objective and there we
know clearly I think as a country they
have already committed to become Net
Zero by 2070 so obviously we will play
very very vital role in being able to
contribute to that particular element
which will help the country to kind of
commit itself the second embracing
digital embracing technology uh
contributes a lot a lot in the way we
kind of promote sustain way of operating
and therefore even when I said 97% of my
policies are soured digitally there is
still that 3% that's left out and can I
keep looking at area by area in figuring
out how some of those elements can be
kind of brought down third can we step
back and start contributing to the
corporates in figuring out how we can
minimize risk itself in the first place
for example a fire incident fire
incident happening for a particular
corporate also results in challenges
from a sustainability standpoint or
let's say from a pollution risk
standpoint if you are able to
meaningfully contribute or minimize some
of the risk incidences then in effect
you are kind of promoting or
contributing to the sustainability
objectives that's why we kind of worked
on what we call as value added Services
initiative over the last eight years and
area by area we have been looking at
what typically causes a loss or what Ty
typically is a risk that an institution
or a corporate could be facing and in
case if you're able to mitigate some of
those losses the possibility of a claim
gets minimized which actually kind of is
environment positive is the way we look
at it so vas will definitely be an area
that we will focus on and we will
continue to look at how we can be even
in our management of funds be more
responsible in the various investment
decisions that we take uh so that's one
other area that we will be kind of
committing towards end of the day
employees or people are our asset and
therefore creating a flexible a friendly
workspace uh and focusing on employee
well-being will definitely be a very
very important agenda in our
sustainability uh initiatives super and
you know when I started out this
conversation gopal I realized that we
are going to get some best practices but
I didn't realize that that this is going
to be a comprehensive look or insight
into how ESG is being realized in a Mari
brand like IC lombar and for that we
must thank you thank you so much for
walking us through all of these various
aspects of ESG breaking them down into
actions and behaviors not just the level
of individuals also teams and the
organization and helping us connect
those dots brilliant chatting with you
and hope to catch up with you again on I
Cafe thank you for being here thanks
thanks thank you so much thanks
everyone you were listening to Il Cafe
we have you covered
h
[Music]